fumikomu ze akuseru
press down hard on the gas
kakehiki wa nai sa sou dayo
that's right, there's no compromise
yoru wo nukeru
we'll slip through the night
nejikomu sa saigo ni
at the final moment push hard
sashihiki zero sa sou dayo
that's right, all the way to zero
hibi wo kezuru
until we wipe away the days
kokoro wo sotto
gently open your heart
hiraite gyutto
hiki yosetara
if you pull it close to you
todoku yo kitto
it will reach you, without a doubt
tsutau yo motto sa aa
it will come, closer, now
iki isoide shiboritotte
we're speeding through life, squeezing it for all of its worth
motsureru ashi
our feet are tied
dakedo mae yori zutto sou tooku he
but we still keep going further
ubaitotte tsukandatte
even if I take it back, and grasp it
kimi janai nara
if you're not the one
imi wa nai no sa
there will be no meaning
dakara haruka kanata
and so we'll go far off into the distance
Hey you, failure.
I have two pieces
of advice for you.
First, if you intend to call
yourself a Shinobi,
stop that revolting cheering of yours.
And second...
a failure will
always be a failure.
There's no changing that!
Do you want to see about that?
You!
Naruto-kun, I get where you're
coming from, believe me.
But all fighting must be done
officially in a match!
The failure beats the gifted genius
through sheer effort...
Wouldn't that make for
an exciting main battle?
I promise you.
I will win no matter what!
Gaara Crushed!!
Youth!
Power!
Explosion!
Hey, Choji!
You're in trouble.
Only the strong ones are left.
Probably the strongest of Hidden Sound
must be that bloke.
And Lee is apparently strong
enough to take on Sasuke!
And particularly that Sand guy!
He's probably
the most dangerous one!
I-I don't care!
I plan to forfeit right away
if that happens...
— So that means...
— Huh?
...you plan to forego
all-you-can-eat BBQ, too, then.
What? Come on!
Don't worry.
If things start getting ugly,
I'll step in and stop the fight,
like I did for Hinata. Okay?
Prime beef tongue, short ribs...
— You can eat what you want.
— Don't dangle food in front of him!
— Besides he didn't step in...
— You can eat whatever you want...
— and stop the fight for Hinata.
— and all you want.
B-B-Q! All right, B-B-Q!
All you can eat!
He doesn't look good.
Watching the previous fight...
Did it get stirred up?
His inner demon!
I'm curious about that guy, Neji, too...
Here's a plan.
Kankuro?
Just a little
information-gathering mission.
— Hey!
— Huh?
What are you doing here
all by yourself?
Shouldn't you be with your friends?
I-It's none of your business, is it?!
Hmmm. Well, well...
That guy... Hyuga Neji, right?
Well, it seems to me that
he didn't reveal the true extent
of his power in that last match.
What's he about?
I'm going to crush him!
Err, that's not what
I was asking.
Besides, this guy's way out of his league...
You seem like a fun guy.
I quite like you.
You're dull.
And I don't like you at all!
I'm going to waste this guy!
We will now resume the battle.
Okay!
You'll be up this time for sure.
Go for it, Lee!
No!
— Huh?
— What?
Seeing as I've come this far,
I'd rather be the last!
Is Lee-san sulking?
Hurry up and get down here...
Safe!
— Hey!
— Don't do anything misleading, idiot!
Gaara
Rock Lee
Oh! Lee-san!
It worked!
If you say you want to go last,
then you won't be last.
It's an application of the same law
that says a stone thrown to hit
a telephone pole will miss,
and a stone thrown to miss
will be a direct hit!
Right! That's my student!
I absolutely did not
want to go last!
I threw them a beauty of a curve!
Threw whom a curve?
Okay, so let me give you
a little piece of "nice" advice.
Right!
Probably no one has noticed yet, but...
That gourd is suspicious!
I see!
Quit with the notes!
You're not going to have time to
read them during the match! Fool!
I see!
He didn't realize that?
Wow, is Lee-san going to be all right?
All right!
Go! Lee!
Yeah!
I am very happy to be squaring
off with you so early in the match.
I don't know what kind of moves
that bowl-cut guy has,
but he will never take Gaara.
Never!
He's fast, to be sure,
but his kick is not all that great.
No...
He's... strong!
Please don't be in such a hurry.
Lee-san...
Be careful, Lee.
Now then... the 9th match...
Begin!
Leaf Hurricane!
Is that...?
Sand?
What an unusual Jutsu...
There's sand in his gourd!
That's...
That's it?
Desert Coffin!
Desert Burial!
Not another horror story like that...
A sand-manipulating Jutsu, eh?
Sounds like trouble.
But let's give it a go!
Even that Lee-san's fast strikes...
have no effect at all!
What's the deal?!
No physical strike is going to
have any effect on him.
What?
The Sand shields and protects Gaara
on its own accord, independently
of any intent on Gaara's part.
That's why... no one has been able
to do it so far...
Injure Gaara, that is.
Crap! He's not moving
a muscle and still...!
Is that it?
Entertain me a bit more...
There's not enough yet!
Blood!
Why is Lee-san only using Taijutsu?
He'll never be able to get close
enough for that!
Why doesn't he step back a bit and
use Ninjutsu or something?
It's not that he doesn't use it.
He can't use it.
Huh?
Lee has almost no Ninjutsu
or Genjutsu skills.
N-No way!
When I first met Lee,
he was completely inept.
He had no talent whatsoever.
What? I can't believe that!
Hey hey!
Certainly...
A ninja who can't do Ninjutsu
and Genjutsu is a rarity.
That's why, the only path open to Lee
as a Ninja was Taijutsu.
But! That's precisely what
makes him a winner!
Huh?
Lee, take them off!
B-But Guy-sensei...!
You told me only to do that
to protect a large group
of very important people!
That's quite all right!
I give you permission!
Are those...?
Weights?
That's some cliché training...
I see!
Ridiculous!
All right, now I can
move easily!
Humph! Does he think
removing some measly little weights
is going to enable him to
outmaneuver Gaara's sand...?
A bit extreme, I'd say, Guy.
Go, Lee!
Right!
Go!
Very close!
Fast!
Amazing...!
Because he can't use
Ninjutsu or Genjutsu...
Therefore, he channeled all
of his time,
all of his energy and...
all of his being into Taijutsu.
Though he can't do any other Jutsu...
He won't lose to anyone...
He is a Taijutsu specialist!
I can't believe it!
Gaara's been injured!
No way...!
Bushy-Brows is even
faster than before!
Was he this strong?!
Youth is... explosion!
Right!
Over here!
Good!
I got him good!
A-Amazing, he's so fast!
The Sand Shield can't keep
up with him!
A direct hit!
A-Amazing.
His strikes are lightning fast...!
I can't even track him
with my eyes!
Uh oh...
Uh oh is right!
That black-circles-under-the-eye
guy is taking some serious blows!
That's not what I meant.
Huh?
W-What the...?!
His face is crumbling right off...!
His whole body is covered
with sand...
There's not a scratch on him!
W-What's with this guy?!
Sure enough, he was
encased in sand, eh.
But, it's been a long time since
I've seen that expression
on Gaara's face.
I felt that he was becoming
more and more unstable
as the Chunin Exam progressed...
So Gaara's other self has
been awakened, eh?
Hey! What is that?
That protected him
against Bushy-Brow's strikes?
Yes... It's Sand Armor.
Armor?
Ordinarily, the Sand Shield
functions to protect him automatically,
but, if by chance,
the Shield is penetrated,
the Sand Armor functions as a second
layer of protection against strikes...
That's Gaara's... absolute defense!
Well then, there's no way
to get him!
He doesn't have any weak points.
No. That's not entirely true...
The Sand Armor is actually
riddled with weak points.
First of all, because it's not automatic,
it uses up a lot of Chakra.
It's also less effective
than the Sand Shield,
and it takes an enormous amount
of physical energy
to keep the sand clinging
to the body like that.
Gaara's having to use the armor...
is proof that he's under pressure.
That Lee is really good...
But, the outcome of the match
is already a given.
He will never beat Gaara!
Is that all?
But what an incredible
defense he has...
no amount of speed is going
to let me get a strike through.
I'll have to do major damage
from above the sand guard.
That will be Lotus!
Yes.
Be ready!
A thin sand guard like that
will be inconsequential
in the face of Lee's high-speed
Lotus slamming down from above.
Hurry up and bring it on!
You asked for it!
He didn't float.
Not just yet!
What an amazing series of kicks!
Even an ordinary Lotus has
a tremendous strain on the body...!
Lee, let this be the finishing blow!
Take this!
Primary Lotus!
I got him...
good!
Right on!
I-It's over!
W-What? This can't be!
He did it! Lee-san's won!
Hey, he isn't dead, is he?
Wha...?!
Huh?!
What?!
hey, can you hear it?
nee kikoe masu ka
sora wa hate shinaku aoku sunde ite
the clear, blue sky goes on and on
umi wa kagiri naku koudai de ite
the ocean spans limitlessly
kimi wa itsumade mo egao de ite
please keep that smile on your face forever
janai to nai chau kara
or else I'll cry
mawari o mimawasa naku temo
You won't have to search around you
mou iin da yo
it's all ok now
kono to no naka ni wa minna ga iru kara
everyone is inside this hand
naki taku natte nige taku natte
when you want to cry, and you want to run away
shiawase o wasure te te shimatta ra
when you forget what happiness is
mina utae
just sing
hikari ga umare yami ga umare ta
light is born, and darkness was born
futatsu wa hitotsu
the two are one
HARUMONIA kanji Te TEREPASHII
harmonia, feel the telepathy
nee kikoe masu ka
hey, can you hear it?
Hey, what happened, Bushy-Brows?!
All of your strength seems
to have disappeared!
You're going to be destroyed
at this rate!
But, hey, Bushy-Brows is smiling!
How can he continue to keep up
a fighting stance
when he's being routed like this?!
Next episode:
"Hot-blooded Dropout! Finally Unleashed, the Forbidden Master Move!"
The expression in Bushy-Brows' eyes
has changed!